<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jakub Krajniak - articles</title><link href="http://jkrajniak.pl/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jkrajniak.pl/feeds/articles.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jkrajniak.pl/</id><updated>2018-03-24T00:04:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Reverse mapping method for complex polymer systems</title><link href="http://jkrajniak.pl/reverse-mapping-method-for-complex-polymer-systems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-24T00:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-24T00:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Krajniak</name></author><id>tag:jkrajniak.pl,2018-03-24:/reverse-mapping-method-for-complex-polymer-systems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We present a comprehensive approach for reverse mapping of complex polymer systems in which the connectivity is created by the simulation of chemical reactions at the coarse-grained scale.
Within the work, we use a recently developed generic adaptive reverse mapping procedure, that we adapt to handle the varying connectivity structure …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We present a comprehensive approach for reverse mapping of complex polymer systems in which the connectivity is created by the simulation of chemical reactions at the coarse-grained scale.
Within the work, we use a recently developed generic adaptive reverse mapping procedure, that we adapt to handle the varying connectivity structure resulting from the chemical reactions.
The method  is independent of the coarse-grained and fine-grained force-fields by design and relies only on a single control parameter.
We employ the approach to reverse map four different systems: a three-component epoxy network, a trimethylol melamine network, a hyperbranched polymer and a polyethylene terephthalate.
In the case of the epoxy network, we use two fine-scale representations: fully atomistic and united-atom.
Whereas the trimethylol melamine network the hyperbranched polymer and the polyethylene terephthalate are reverse mapped to the fully atomistic description.
After the reverse mapping, we examine the fine-grained structure by comparing the radial distribution functions with respect to the control parameter. Moreover, in the case of the epoxy we perform tensile-test experiments and examine the resulting Young's modulus.
In all cases, we show how the properties of the reverse mapped systems depend on the control parameters. In general, we see that the results are relatively insensitive to the control parameter and the resulting atomistic systems are stable. Only for the trimethylol melamine network, we notice chemically incorrect conformations when the reverse mapping is performed too fast.  We provide a remedy for this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DOI: 10.1002/jcc.25129&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/jcc.25129"&gt;(full text)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
    &lt;iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/dQw4w9WgXcQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>PhD project</title><link href="http://jkrajniak.pl/phd-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Krajniak</name></author><id>tag:jkrajniak.pl,2018-03-24:/phd-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Multiscale modeling at the soft/hard matter interface: linking nanoscale up to the micro-mesoscale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SBO project InterPoCo is a 4-year strategic research project that will lay the foundations for the H-INT-S program by taking a detailed look at the interface in steel fiber composites and self-healing capsules in polymer …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Multiscale modeling at the soft/hard matter interface: linking nanoscale up to the micro-mesoscale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SBO project InterPoCo is a 4-year strategic research project that will lay the foundations for the H-INT-S program by taking a detailed look at the interface in steel fiber composites and self-healing capsules in polymer matrices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sim-flanders.be/project/interpoco"&gt;InterPoCo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="conferences"></category></entry><entry><title>Generic adaptive resolution approach to refeverse mapping of polymer melts</title><link href="http://jkrajniak.pl/generic-adaptive-resolution-approach-to-refeverse-mapping-of-polymer-melts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-10-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Krajniak</name></author><id>tag:jkrajniak.pl,2016-10-14:/generic-adaptive-resolution-approach-to-refeverse-mapping-of-polymer-melts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past two decades, coarse-grained (CG) simulation has become an important method that allows exploring
behaviour of larger (bio-)polymer systems over longer time scales. Although many properties of polymers can be
analysed at the CG level, some properties strictly depend on the presence of fine-scale degrees of freedom …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past two decades, coarse-grained (CG) simulation has become an important method that allows exploring
behaviour of larger (bio-)polymer systems over longer time scales. Although many properties of polymers can be
analysed at the CG level, some properties strictly depend on the presence of fine-scale degrees of freedom.
Therefore, there is a demand for a computational tool that reintroduces atomistic details in an already performed
coarse-grained simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this contribution, we present a generic method of reverse mapping that is based on the adaptive resolution
scheme (AdResS). In AdResS simulation, one brings together two spatial domains, modelled at two different
scales, in a concurrent simulation. This is done by defining a hybrid region where, by the spatial-dependent
switching function, particles change from the coarse-grained to the atomistic resolution. We use this
method from a different perspective by treating a whole simulation box as a hybrid region and using the time-dependent
switching function. Additionally, we introduce bonded potentials that scale with changing resolution. This
approach prevents the introduction of a huge potential energy that could arise in the early stage where the
resolution is close to the coarse-grained. We use our method to reconstruct polymer melts and complex polymer
networks from the coarse-grained to the all-atom state. We compare conformational and dynamical properties of
reconstructed systems with the reference atomistic simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mmm2016.iop.org/IOP/media/uploaded/EVIOP/event_817/MMM_2016_Abstracts.pdf"&gt;(abstract book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="conferences"></category></entry><entry><title>Generic adaptive resolution method for reverse mapping of polymers from coarse-grained to atomistic descriptions</title><link href="http://jkrajniak.pl/generic-adaptive-resolution-method-for-reverse-mapping-of-polymers-from-coarse-grained-to-atomistic-descriptions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-29T00:04:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-29T00:04:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Krajniak</name></author><id>tag:jkrajniak.pl,2016-09-29:/generic-adaptive-resolution-method-for-reverse-mapping-of-polymers-from-coarse-grained-to-atomistic-descriptions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose a new generic approach for reverse mapping from coarse-grained to atomistic scale based on the adaptive resolution scheme (AdResS).
In AdResS simulation, two spatial domains, modelled at two different scales, are brought together in a concurrent simulation by defining a hybrid region where particles can …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose a new generic approach for reverse mapping from coarse-grained to atomistic scale based on the adaptive resolution scheme (AdResS).
In AdResS simulation, two spatial domains, modelled at two different scales, are brought together in a concurrent simulation by defining a hybrid region where particles can switch representation from one model to another.
We use AdResS as a central part of a reverse mapping algorithm from a different perspective by treating the whole simulation box as a hybrid region and changing the resolution as a function of time during the course of a molecular dynamics simulation.
The proposed method depends only on a single parameter that controls the reverse mapping process and it is independent of atomistic and coarse-grained force-fields.
We performed the reverse mapping of three different systems, a simple molecule (dodecane), a polymer chain (polyethylene) and a ring molecule (trimethylol melamine) with a degree of coarse-graining, ranging from two to ten heavy atoms.
The conformational and dynamical properties of the reconstructed systems are in excellent agreement with the reference atomistic simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DOI: 10.1021/acs.jctc.6b00595&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/acs.jctc.6b00595"&gt;(full text)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Molecular dynamics simulations of polymerization with forward and backward reactions</title><link href="http://jkrajniak.pl/molecular-dynamics-simulations-of-polymerization-with-forward-and-backward-reactions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-18T00:04:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-07-18T00:04:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jakub Krajniak</name></author><id>tag:jkrajniak.pl,2016-07-18:/molecular-dynamics-simulations-of-polymerization-with-forward-and-backward-reactions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We look into the polymerization of polyethylene terephthalate (PET) at the coarse-grained level as an example of a polycondensation reaction with water as a byproduct.
To fully simulate this reaction, we develop novel parallel algorithms that allow creating and removing the byproduct molecule appearing as a result of the chemical …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We look into the polymerization of polyethylene terephthalate (PET) at the coarse-grained level as an example of a polycondensation reaction with water as a byproduct.
To fully simulate this reaction, we develop novel parallel algorithms that allow creating and removing the byproduct molecule appearing as a result of the chemical reactions during the molecular dynamics simulation. We tackle the problem of a smooth byproduct molecule creation by introducing the corresponding forces gradually, via a time-dependent switching function that prevents large increases in the potential energy.
Moreover, the implemented methods allow incorporating the reverse process, the hydrolysis reaction, in which the byproduct molecule attacks newly created bonds and reverts to the state before the emission.
The methods are implemented in a publicly available software package, and are easily accessible using a newly created domain specific language that describes chemical reactions in an input configuration file.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="articles"></category></entry></feed>